Guide to the Robert Murray Haig Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Robert Murray Haig Papers
[ca. 1927]-1949
Haig, Robert Murray, 1887-1953.
126 boxes.
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078849
Biographical Note
Economist. Haig was professor of economics at Columbia University.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, 1927-1949, and lecture notes, manuscripts of articles and addresses, and material relating to Haig's various activities such as the Commission on State Aid and the New York Power Commission.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 3 series:
Series I. Manuscripts and Documents
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Correspondence Box Files
Subjects
Power Authority of the State of New York.; Columbia University--Faculty.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1865-1950.; Economics--Study and teaching.; New York Power Commission.; College teachers.; Economists.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1953 M-53 Haig, Mrs. Robert M. Gift
- Series I. Manuscripts and Documents
  - Richmond 1945 (Box 1)
  - Special assessments 1 (Box 2)
  - Special assessments 2 (Box 3)
  - Mss. 1 (see also boxes 12-13) (Box 4)
  - Mss 2 (Box 5)
  - Mss 3 (Box 6)
  - New York State economy committees (Box 7)
  - Educational Finance (Box 8)
  - National Institute of Public Administration (Box 9)
  - California Tax Commission 1 (Box 10)
  - California Tax Commission 2 (Box 11)
  - Mss. 4 (see also boxes 4-6) (Box 12)
  - Mss. 5 (Box 13)
  - Lecture notes 1 (Box 14)
  - Lecture notes 2 (Box 15)
  - Lecture notes 3 (Box 16)
  - Lecture notes 4 (Box 17)
  - Lecture notes 5 (Box 18)
  - Lecture notes 6 (Box 19)
  - Lecture notes 7 (Box 20)
  - Lecture notes 8 (Box 21)
  - Lecture notes 9 (Box 22)
  - Lecture notes 10 (Box 23)
  - Puerto Rico1 (see also boxes 51-55) (Box 24)
  - Puerto Rico 2 (Box 25)
  - Concept of income 1 (Box 26)
  - Concept of income 2 (Box 27)
  - Concept of income 3 (Box 28)
  - Concept of income 4 (Box 29)
  - Concept of income 5 (Box 30)
  - Concept of income 6 (Box 31)
  - Concept of income 7 (Box 32)
  - Mastick Commission 1931 (Box 33)
  - Mastick Commission 1932 (1) (Box 34)
  - Mastick Commission 1932 (2) (Box 35)
  - Cost of compliance 1 (Box 36)
  - Cost of compliance 2 (Box 37)
  - McAneny Commission 1 (Box 38)
  - McAneny Commission 2 (Box 39)
  - McAneny Commission 3 (Box 40)
  - McAneny Commission 4 (Box 41)
  - McAneny Commission 5 (Box 42)
  - Tax exempt securities- Shamburg case 1942-43 (1) (Box 43)
  - Tax exempt securities- Shamburg case 1942-43 (2) (Box 44)
  - Tax exempt securities- Shamburg case 1942-43 (3) (Box 45)
  - NY State Power Commission 1 (Box 46)
  - NY State Power Commission 2 (Box 47)
  - NY State Power Commission 3 (Box 48)
  - NY State Power Commission 4 (Box 49)
  - NY State Power Commission 5 (Box 50)
  - Puerto Rico 3 (see also boxes 24-25) (Box 51)
  - Puerto Rico 4 (Box 52)
  - Puerto Rico 5 (Box 53)
  - Puerto Rico 6 (Box 54)
  - Puerto Rico 7 (Box 55)
  - Australia (Box 56)
  - Committee on State Aid 1 (Box 57)
  - Committe on State Aid 2 (Box 58)
  - Federal corporate income tax 1 (Box 59)
  - Federal corporate income tax 2 (Box 60)
  - Federal corporate income tax 3 (Box 61)
  - Federal state 1 (Box 62)
  - Federal state 2 (Box 63)
  - Federal state 3 (Box 64)
  - Federal state 4 (Box 65)
  - Federal state 5 (Box 66)
  - Mayor's Committee 1952 (1) (Box 67)
  - Mayor's Committee 1952 (2) (Box 68)
  - Mayor's Committee 1952 (3) (Box 69)
  - Mayor's Committe 1952 (4) (Box 70)
  - Capitol gains 1 (Box 71)
  - Capitol gains 2 (Box 72)
  - Capitol gains 3 (Box 73)
  - Capitol gains 4 (Box 74)
  - Capitol gains 5 (Box 75)
  - Freedom Committee 1 (Box 76)
  - Freedom Committee 2 (Box 77)
  - Freedom Committee 3 (Box 78)
  - Freedom Committee 4 (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous 1 (Box 80)
  - Miscellaneous 2 (Box 81)
  - Miscellaneous 3 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous 4 (Box 83)
  - Miscellaneous 5 (Box 84)
  - Miscellaneous 6 (Box 85)
  - Miscellaneous 7 (Box 86)
  - Miscellaneous 8 (Box 87)
  - Miscellaneous 9 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous 10 (Box 89)
  - Miscellaneous 11 (Box 90)
  - Miscellaneous 12 (Box 91)
  - Miscellaneous 13 (Box 92)
  - Miscellaneous 14 (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous 15 (Box 94)
  - Miscellaneous 16 (Box 95)
  - Miscellaneous 17 (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous 18 (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous 19 (Box 98)
  - Miscellaneous 20 (Box 99)
  - Miscellaneous 21 (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous 22 (Box 101)
  - Tax Revision Commission 1 (Box 102)
  - Tax Revision Commission 2 (Box 103)
  - Tax Revision Commission 3 (Box 104)
  - Tax Revision Commission 4 (Box 105)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1913-1935 (Box 106)
    [Gift of Carl Shoup,1990]
  - Class rolls and records (Box 106)
    [Gift of Carl Shoup, 1990]
  - Finance 106 final exam (Box 106)
  - Economics 101 reading assignment1936 (Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1917-20 (Box 106)
  - Publications, 1913-1926 (Box 106)
  - Printed Material from: "Interamerican High Commission" 1920; NYS Temporary Emergency Relief Committee, 1931-34; Federal Emergency Relief Administration 1933-35 (Box 106)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - A-B (Box 107)
  - C-D (Box 108)
  - E-F (Box 109)
  - G-H (Box 110)
  - I-L (Box 111)
  - M (Box 112)
  - N-P (Box 113)
  - Q-R (Box 114)
  - S-T (Box 115)
  - U-Z (Box 116)
  - Student cards, A-F (Box 117)
  - Student cards, G-M -- Seating charts -- 23 miscellaneous R-Y cards (Box 118)
- Series III: Correspondence Box Files
  24 file boxes in 8 record storage cartons. The file coxes are arranged alphabetically and roughly by year, although different dates are scattered through each box; boxes have several folders of material before the alphabetical sequences, with dates which correspond to that of their boxes
  - 1917, 1914, 1915 (Box 119)
  - 1937 (Box 119)
  - 1936 (Box 119)
  - 1937-38 (Box 120)
  - 1937-38 (Box 120)
  - 1939-40 (Box 120)
  - 1939 (Box 121)
  - 1939-40 (Box 121)
  - 1940 (Box 121)
  - 1941 (Box 122)
  - 1940-41 (Box 122)
  - 1940-41 (Box 122)
  - 1941-42 (Box 123)
  - 1941-42 (Box 123)
  - 1942-43 (Box 123)
  - 1942-43 (Box 124)
  - 1943-44 (Box 124)
  - 1944-45 (Box 124)
  - 1945-46 (Box 125)
  - 1946 (Box 125)
  - 1947 (Box 125)
  - 1947-48 (Box 126)
  - 1948-49 (Box 126)
  - 1949-51 (Box 126)